<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason A. Evans</title>
    <description>Never too old for lego</description>
    <link>http://jasonaevans.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jasonaevans.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 18:35:26 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 18:35:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>QA and the Agile Process (Mindset and Team Dynamics)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A good place to start this post is with the Agile Manifesto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Individuals and interactions over processes and tools”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically meaning that the communication and interactions which team members have, is more important than the tools and
process which you have in place. Typically with those companies where the QA work-flow is still defined as waterfall, the
QA team has little interaction with the other members of the team and overall project until the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So firstly let us examine what quality means, I personally like the definition given in the PMBOK which is
&lt;strong&gt;“Quality - The degree to which a set of inherent characteristics fulfills requirements”&lt;/strong&gt;. But how does QA implement
such concepts, one of the key points is via Quality Management which I define as &lt;strong&gt;”ensure
quality at a specific level throughout the entire process of the development cycle and to deliver a desired level of
quality to the customer”&lt;/strong&gt;, and quite often the idea of “entire” is eroded by a waterfall process and the focus is just
on the “delivery”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Involving QA team members early means that they can apply Quality Management principles throughout the project. But that
is not the only reason why you should involve QA people early. They can bring real value into planning and execution of
projects, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They are often Subject Matter Experts, they can offer constructive and useful feedback as to how a new feature will
interact with existing process. In fact a lot of the time involving QA is like involving your customers as QA are
consistently using your product on a daily basis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They have an understanding of problem areas within your software, they know where the quirks are, they know areas
which could be improved on to increase customer satisfaction. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only can it be beneficial to have QAs involved in the early stages of projects, it is also beneficial to have them
test early, which I refer to as the “test early and test often approach”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing early allows for the detection of bugs and issues earlier on in the process. A bug fixed in the early stages
can have both a saving in regards to the financial cost but also the time cost in the development process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing early also enables QAs to ensure that projects are progressing in line with the overall acceptance testing
criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing often is an iterative approach to the above. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example work-flow is as follow, (we will go into further details in the next few posts)
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/qa-workflow.png&quot; alt=&quot;QA Work-flow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;team-dynamics&quot;&gt;Team Dynamics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more common concepts in Agile development is to have small manageable teams, for example having a team of 4
developers. As part of this team dynamic, you should consider embedding a QA person directly into the team. The benefits
of this are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;QA testers can share their knowledge with Engineers directly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A relationship of trust can be built, rather than an “Us vs Them” mentality which often exists in the software
development environment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Empowering QA along the development process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;QAs can also have a clear channel of communication to the Product Owner, thus allowing for more transparency when defining the project objectives through their tests. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also experimented with DoTing which is Developer on Testing (I will cover this at a later date), and these
types of dynamics are beneficial because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows QA testers to share their knowledge with Engineers on the testing process, how something will be tested, why it
will be tested and when it will be tested.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enables QA testers to execute the “Test early and test often” concept, as team members are closely communicating an
Engineer can ask a QA tester to have a look at their progress and smoke test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 22:01:04 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jasonaevans.com/qa-agile-process-mindset-and-team-dynamics</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jasonaevans.com/qa-agile-process-mindset-and-team-dynamics</guid>
        
        <category>QA,</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Engineering,</category>
        
        <category>Agile</category>
        
        
        <category>Agile,</category>
        
        <category>QA</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>QA and the Agile Process (Introduction)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spoken to a lot of people involved in software development, Engineers, Managers, CTOs, QAs, and when I ask about QA and Agile many struggle to come up with an answer and quite often I am told that they leave QA as a waterfall process. So does QA fit into the Agile process ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a multipart part series on integrating QA into the Agile workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../qa-agile-process-mindset-and-team-dynamics&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1&lt;/strong&gt; Will explore the mindset changes needed to have QA work within Agile, and will also cover the team dynamics.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 22:01:04 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jasonaevans.com/qa-agile-process-introduction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jasonaevans.com/qa-agile-process-introduction</guid>
        
        <category>QA,</category>
        
        <category>Software</category>
        
        <category>Engineering,</category>
        
        <category>Agile</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
